Finding aid for Manuel Luis Quezon papers, 1909-1944
Bentley Historical Library
- General Correspondence, 1909-1944; 21 reels
  - President of the Senate
    - July 25, 1931-June 29, 1932 (Reel 15)
      Ramon Fernandez, esp. Quezon to R. Fernandez. 5 page letter (Spanish), Jan 25, 1932, re: a concerned group of citizens who wired directly to Bureau of Internal Affairs stressing desire for immediate independence, Quezon reprimands them slightly for not going thru the mission (greeting to "Mi querido compadre")
      Philippine Sugar Association, esp: 7 page letter to T. Roosevelt, Jr. (March 11, 1932) with charts and tables, etc., copy of letter to Quezon [much correspondence on sugar industry]
      Antonio de las Alas (Acting Speaker) esp.: a 4 page letter from Quezon (May 25, 1932) re: independence issue and Philippine legislators' contacts with the mission
      Juan Sumulong, esp. Quezon to Sumulong. 4 page letter (Feb. 10, 1932) re: Sumulong's opposition to the publicity fund for the Mission to the U.S.
      Also letter from Quezon to Senator [?] (of Pasay, Rizil) long 7 page letter in Tagalog (Jan. 8, 1932) re: politics in Manila and Philippines, Democratas, Osmeña, Mission to U.S., etc. [possibly to Sumulong]
    - June 29, 1932-August 10, 1933 (Reel 16)
      Highlights of roll 16, June 29, 1932-August 10, 1933, with notes and comments by Michael Cullinane
      Heavy correspondence with "Osrox" (Washington) re: stateside legislation, etc.
      F. McIntyre (Philippine Trade Commission)
      C. Osias
      Amando Avancena (Cadiz, Negros Occidental) and other sugar related correspondence and memorandums in Quezon's possession
      Many U. S. Congressmen (esp. Senators Hawes and Hare)
      Roy Howard (New York)--a close friend who refers to Quezon as "My dear Casey"
      J. L. Headington (V. Pres., Philippine Button Company) re: Philippine business
      E. D. Hester (advisor to Governor-General)
      C. P. Romulo
      E. Quirino
      F. Buencamino
      J. Bocobo
      R. Fernandez
      Quintin Paredes (Speaker pro tem, House)
      S. Osmeña (slight during this period, i.e. personal correspondence)
      Resolution by a Committee of American Democrats in Philippines
      Federico Mangahas (The Tribune) re: a letter by Quezon (not sent) in response to a "vicious" attack by Mangahas in press (Dec., 1932)
      Significant correspondence:
      Aguinaldo to Osmeña (Washington). Letter (Aug. 12, 1932) re: his desire to know the truth about what's going on in Washington, he repeats all the anti-Mission information in Manila press
      Osmeña to Aguinaldo. 22 page letter (September 30, 1932) a complete reply, answering each of the above accusations, explaining in detail the Mission's work and their position on H-H-C Bill
      Osias to Osmeña 5 page letter (Aug. 22, 1932) re: a denial by Osias that he has attacked the independence mission
      E. D. Hester to Quezon. Letter (Aug. 27, 1932) re: Philippine tariff
      Osmeña to Quezon. Letter (Oct. 3, 1932) re: his letter and correspondence with Aguinaldo
      Quezon to Romulo. 4 page letter (not sent), Nov. 1, 1932, re: Senate maneuvering and his alleged favoring of opposition Sen. (i.e. Relto) over his governorship
      Quezon to Senator Teofilo Sison. 3 page letter and enclosure (Nov. 11, 1932) re: a tribute to General Luna
      Quezon to Senator B. Aquino. Letter (Spanish), Nov. 14, 1932 re: his work in the U.S.
      Quezon to MacArthur. Cable (n.d. but after Dec. 30, 1932) re: MacArthur's stand on Philippine independence
      M. Kalaw to Quezon. 2 page letter (Spanish), Jan. 4, 1933, re: his desire to be ideologically reunited with Quezon, but with certain guarantees first, in Nationalista stand on independence
      Quezon to M. Kalaw. 13 pages of drafts Jan 8, 1933, mailed Jan. 9, 1933. re: his reply with much explanation of his activities in Washington during debates over Jones Bill and Clarke Amendment, mainly re: Quezon's split with the Mission leaders
      Luis R. de Luzuriaga (writing from Cebu) to Quezon. Letter (Feb. 19, 1933) re: sugar question and business proposal to Quezon, he is currently working for Socony-Vacuum Corporation in Cebu, was a former associate of Rafael Alunan
      M. Kalaw to Quezon. Letter (May 29, 1933) re: common action by both legislative mission and independence mission (in Washington) over independence bills
      Quezon to Harrison. Cable (July 2, 1933) re: obtaining Harrison's support of the "anti" view and Osmeña's prior fears with Clarke amendment
      Harrison to Quezon Cable (July 5, 1933) --Harrison's favorable reply
      Ramon Torres (Bago, Negros Occidental) to Quezon. 3 page letter in Spanish (July 4, 1933)--he is an "anti" and will support Quezon but wants to maintain party unity if possible, some about Negros Occidental politics
      Quezon to R. Torres. 4 page letter in Spanish (after 5 drafts) (July 8, 1933)--Quezon's reply, explaining his opposition to H-H-C Bill, and the difficulties with Osmeña over H-H-C and why split is necessary
      Some correspondence over financial matter is found between Murphy and V. Singson Encarnacion (Acting Secretary of Finance)
    - August 11, 1933-June 7, 1934 (Reel 17)
      Highlights of roll 17, August 11, 1933-June 7, 1934, with notes and comments by Michael Cullinane
      Many U. S. Congressmen, esp. Senator McDuffie, Representative Sabath (Iowa), Senator King and Senator P. Harrison
      Some copies of Secretary of War to Governor-General
      Sugar Philippines--lobby of Philippine Sugar interests in Washington, esp.: Rafael Alunan--much on sugar in 1934
      Creed F. Cox (Chief, Bureau Insular Affairs)
      William Baldwin (New York)
      F. D. R. on occasion
      I. Garaldon (while both were in Washington)
      J. Bocobo (memos re: H-H-C Bill, "Plebicite", etc.)
      V. Singson Encarnacion to Murphy re: financial matters
      Quirico Abeto (Secretary of Justice) in Spanish
      T. Kalaw (National Library)
      E. Aguinaldo (mostly re: his going to U.S. with independence mission of legislation)
      Frank Murphy
      Quezon to Osmeña. Letter (not sent) (Oct. 15, 1933) re: minority caucus in Senate headed by Osmeña and also re: H-H-C Bill
      Quezon to Osmeña. Letter (Oct. 19, 1933) re: some questions sent by Osmeña
      Tirona (Rep., Cavite). 3 page letter (Spanish) (Oct. 31, 1933) A very sharp criticism of Quezon, mainly due to his stateside activities as nominal head independence mission: "...en ver de asistir a las sesiones de Copgreso, y trabajar cerca del mismo por nuestra indep., se fue usted directamente a Monrovia, para to mar vacaciones a costa de Juan de la cruz..." Tirona stresses that he is unafraid of Quezon or anyone!
      V. Singson Encarnacion to J. Vargas. Letter (Dec. 11, 1933) and (Dec. 21, 1933) re: mostly sugar and other Philippine crops and resources
      Recto to Governor-General. 5 page letter (Jan. 7, 1934) re: constitutional problems
      Memorandum on Philippine-American trade relations by Quezon (Jan., 1934) 17 pages
      American Philippine policy 13 pages (Jan., 1934) 13 drafts (one to be signed Quezon, Quirino, Gabaldon, Guevara
      C. E. Russell to Quezon. Letter (Jan. 16, 1934) re: the failing of Quezon's memorandum (above) and how it will not get the desired results
      Recto-Paredes to Quezon. Letter (Feb. 3, 1934) re: a resolution on Philippine independence passed by a mass meeting in Manila the day before
      G. T. Peabody (Mindanao-Pacific Corp., Ltd.) to Quezon. Letter (Feb. 15, 1934) re: economic situation
      Quezon to I. Gabaldon. Letter (March 24, 1934) re: Quezon's explanation to I.G. about Quezon's actions concerning the H-H-C Bill and subsequent
      Cabrera to Quezon. Telegram (April 4, 1934) re: defeating Roxas
      Roxas to Quezon. 2 page letter (May 10, 1934) a somewhat angry letter reacting to Quezon's quote in papers about him, Roxas explains he is a "technical man" not desiring to bother with politics, wants to go back to the farm, says he's not a "pro" or any other political classification--he then praises Quezon
    - June 7, 1934-November 14, 1935 (Reel 18)
      Highlights of roll 18 (part), June 7, 1934-November 14, 1935, with notes and comments by Michael Cullinane
      Frequent memorandums re: economic problems: tariffs, trade, sugar, other crops, and products, esp. by V. Singson Encarnacion, and R. Alunan (P. Sugar Assoc.)
      Creed Cox
      Senator Howes, McDuffie, etc.
      Neuss, Hesslein, and Company, Inc. (New York)
      Cordace Institution (J.S. McDaniel)
      Hanson, Orth and Stevenson, Inc. (London)
      Roy Howard (Scripts-Howard Newspapers--New York)--heavy in late 1935, early 1936
      Leonidas Dyer (Lawyer, St. Louis, Missouri)
      MacArthur, Douglas
      F. A. Delgado (President, Comm. from Philippines--late 1935)
      Morgan Shuster (New York)
      "Don Miguel"
      C. M. Recto
      T. M. Kalaw
      P. Guevara re: his running for office with or without Quezon's support depending on his stand
      Vicente Lim re: Philippine national defense, some on Americanization of Filipinos and its negative results
      Senator Hawes to Roxas. Letter (Nov. 7, 1934) re: Hawes' praise of Roxas
      Dr. [?] to Quezon. Letter (n.d.) very interesting response to a Quezon letter re: nationalist movements in Indonesia and some about Javanese nobility
      J. Yulo to Quezon. Letter (Jan. 7, 1935) re: Quezon's appointment of him to Supreme Court, a personal explanation of why he is opposed
      Quezon to Murphy. Letter (Jan. 8, 1935) re: (among others) the Sakdalistas in Tayabas and Laguna
      Quezon to Malcolm. Letter (Jan. 21, 1935)--a critique of Malcolm's manuscript (book) about Quezon's political machine and other issues
      Osmeña to Quezon. Telegram (March 18, 1935) re: coalition prospects
      Vargas to Quezon. Radiogram (April 1, 1935) re: Sumulong's stand on coalition and some on activities of the - Sakdalistas
      Vargas to Quezon. Radiogram (April 21, 1935) re: Sumulong's stand on coalition and some on activities of the - Sakdalistas
      Vargas to Quezon. Radiogram (April 24, 1935) re: Sumulong's stand on coalition and some on activities of the - Sakdalistas
      Quezon to Vargas. Radiogram (April 24, 1935 re: Sumulong's stand on coalition and some on activities of the - Sakdalistas
      Vargas to Quezon. Radiogram (April 29, 1935) re: Sumulong's article "Highlights given" --article: "After Coalition the Decline" in Manila papers April 27th.
      Vargas to Quezon. Radiogram (May 3, 1935) re: Sumulong's article, Quezon's stand
      Confederate n.d. reports to Quezon re: Sakdalista uprising early May, 1935
      C. Rumulo to Quezon. 8 page letter (May 15, 1935) re: political situation. Report to Quezon including Sakdalista revolt, newspapers stands on day's issues --writing as the publisher of D-M-H-M Newspapers (Debate, Mabuhay, Herald, Monday mail)
      Recto Roxas Alunan to Quezon. Radiogram (May 21, 1935)
      Yulo to Quezon. Letter (May 27, 1935) re: national assembly for coalition and pres. campaign, enclosed a brief statement re: ones against Sakdals in various towns
      Quezon to Sumulong. Telegram (Aug. 30, 1935) re: Sumulong's attack on him.
      Laurel to Quezon. Letter (Sept. 2, 1935) re: Sumulong's article, he wants Quezon to deny the quote ascribed to Quezon in Bulletin (which he cites and which serves as the main thrust in Sumulong's argument)
      Quezon to Laurel. Letter (Sept. 5, 1935): he denies above statement, says he never made it at all
      Quezon to Paredes. Letter (Oct. 24, 1935): offers him a post as Resid. Comm.
      Paredes to Quezon. Letter 14 pages (Nov. 3, 1935)--expresses his continued opposition to complete coalition (or fusion); also explains that he can do more as speaker of National Assembly; he explains its functions and possibilities
      Quezon to Paredes. 19 page letter (Nov. 6, 1935)--presents his side and views regarding the National Assembly
      Aguinaldo to Secretary of War. 3 page letter (Nov. 3, 1935) re: his particular distaste for recent election conduct, especially for Commonwealth President, where he lost, claims widespread fraud occurred, P.C. harassment, etc.
  - President of the Commonwealth of the Philippines
    The President of the Commonwealth of the Philippines (1935-1944; Reels 18-21) subseries covers Quezon's tenure as president, the passage of social legislation, and the war with Japan. For the years 1936 to 1944, there is substantially reduced documentation compared to the previous two subseries and almost no correspondence for 1938.
    - November 15, 1935-February 26, 1937 (Reel 18)
      Highlights of roll 18 (part), November 15, 1935-February 26, 1937, with notes and comments by Michael Cullinane
      Quezon to Jose E. Romero (Floor Leader). 10 page letter (March 15, 1936) re: rights of National Assembly members
    - March 11, 1937-October 18, 1939 (Reel 19)
      Highlights of roll 19, March 11, 1937-October 18, 1939, with notes and comments by Michael Cullinane
      L. G. Dyer (Lawyer, St. Louis) re: Philippine cause, aiding Quezon
      J. O. Adler (New York Times) and S. Fisher, Jr. (New York Times)
      Paul V. McNutt
      General C. Burnett (Chief, R.I.A.)--1939
      Frank Murphy, Roy Howard--continuing personal correspondence, esp: Quezon to Murphy, July 8, 1937 where Quezon thanks for Murphy for his recent hospitality in Detroit
      Harry H. Woodring (Secretary of War--late 1937)
      Francis Sayre
      Franklin Delano Roosevelt--on occasion
      Many U.S. Congressmen, e.g. Senator Hawes, Tydings, P. Harrison and Sabath, King and Representative Kocialkowski re: Joint Preparation Committee on Philippine Affairs
      Much correspondence with Joint Preparation Committee on Philippine Affairs with Osmeña, the head of Philippine delegation; many letters re: Joint Preparation Committee on Philippine Affairs work in letters of Osmeña to Quezon, especially Jan. 1939, much of which concern sugar; these letters include enclosures of Osmeña's correspondence with others in Washington, especially Senator Hawes and W. C. Forbes [helping Osmeña]
      Osmeña to Quezon. Radiogram (July 10, 1939) re: Quezon's efforts to change constitution so he can run for a second term of office as Commonwealth. President; Osmeña favorable to idea
      J. M. Elizalde (London and Resid. Comm.) "Mike"--regular and official correspondence
      F. Buencamino, Jr. (London)--business mostly
      J. Vargas, esp.:
      Vargas to Quezon. Cable (April 3, 1937) re: legislation endorsements of Quezon's activities in Washington
      Quezon to Vargas. 4 page letter (April 8, 1937) (en route Mexico) re: his progress in U.S.
      Q. Paredes
      [Roxas, Romero, Razon]
      Jose Yulo ("My Dear Joe")
      Charles Romulo: long 7 page letter (many drafts), Oct. 30, 1937, re: history and contribution of Philippine Herald on its anniversary
      Locsin (Negros Occidental) include 8 page letter to Quezon (Aug. 3, 1937) re: many items, esp. trade, tariffs on agricultural goods, etc. and U.S. Congressional action
      Speaker [Montilla (Negros Occidental)]? esp. 6 page letter from Quezon, Aug. 30, 1937, re: Quezon's views on Philippine party coalition and fusion (1st draft); also Quezon to Speaker, long 3 page letter n.d. re: coalition and fusion
    - October 18, 1939-November 30, 1942 (Reel 20)
      Highlights of roll 20, October 18, 1939-November 30, 1942, with notes and comments by Michael Cullinane
      J. M. Elizalde (Resid. Comm.)--very heavy official correspondence
      Frank Murphy, especially to "Justice" Murphy, a petition from the Philippine Assembly (Jan. 29, 1940) re: getting clemency for F. Buencamino, Jr.
      Sergio Osmeña (while in U.S.)
      LaGuardia (New York) re: Philippine entry in New York World's Fair--eventually no funds to set up facilities
      G. Fairchild
      F. D. Roosevelt, much in Dec. 1942 to Jan. 1942 re: Philippine loyalty, requesting funds, international priorities, etc.
      Secretary Harold Ickes (Interior), C. Holl, Abe Fortas, Henry Stimson (Much after Pearl Harbor)
      Manuel Avila Camacho (Pres. Mexico): Quezon congratulations for winning Presidency of Mexico
      W. P. Simms (Solipp--Howard Newspapers) Quezon attacks them for their attacks on him, blames U.S. for 55 year of misrule (Dec. 4, 1941)
      F. Sayre
      MacArthur, slight until Pearl Harbor, then quite heavy; Memorandum of military adviser (Dec. 9, 1939) 20 pages
      Claude Buss (Executive Assistant to High Commissioner)
      Sergio Osmeña, esp.:
      Osmeña to Quezon. 2 page memo (confidential), Dec. 27, 1939, re: Osmeña's dislike of Elizalde's actions of belittling work of mission in Washington, Osmeña says Elizalde (after his return) overstressed his contribution to the cause, Osmeña defends the mission [notes also that he is unable to get an appointment with Quezon]
      Osmeña to Quezon. 3 page confidential letter (Dec. 31, 1939) asks if Mission can be given opportunity to answer each of Elizalde's charges
      Yulo, esp. (in Washington and Manila)
      Quezon and Vargas to Yulo. Radiogram (Oct. 25, 1940) re: the selection of Ramon Torres as compromise candidate for Governor of Negros
      Quezon to Yulo. 2 page letter (Feb. 24, 1941) re: an explanation of political points which Yulo was disturbed over, also re: the near "Fight in Negros" between inter-party factions, also re: the Yulo--Alunan dispute
      R. Alunan, esp. (Secretary of Interior) Quezon to R. Alunan. Letter (May 6, 1941) re: the necessity of Philippine loyalty to U.S. at this time of stress, especially in response to Socialist Communist anti-imperialist dogma--should outlaw their meetings (wants Alunan to do this within municipalities and provinces
      Leon Guinto, esp. 5 page memo to Quezon (May 23, 1941) "A Plan to Check Communism in Philippines"
      Ricardo D. Miranda (Acting Governor, Province of Davao) esp. a letter (Feb. 6, 1942) to Teofisto Guingona (Commissioner for Mindanao and Sulu) 5 pages plus letter and enclosures--i.e. events in area to do with Japanese attack during December, 1941.
      Mayor Delgado (Cebu), especially
      Delgado to Quezon, Cable (Feb. 7, 1941) re: the Visayas--"Civilian morale good"
      Other correspondence on Visayas exists for this period, talk of bolstering up the area (especially Cebu, Negros, Panay)
      5 page memo (May 5, 1941) by Quezon to National Assembly re: national security in the event of war
      Quezon to "People of America" (Dec. 20, 1941) re: Philippine plight, plea for support
    - December 3, 1942-August 1944 (Reel 21)
      Highlights of roll 21, December 3, 1942-August 1944, with notes and comments by Michael Cullinane
      Communications (almost entirely) with individuals in the United States:
      Franklin Delano Roosevelt
      Abe Fortas (Acting Secretary of Interior)
      MacArthur (much from Australia)
      Cordell Hull
      Walter Lippman (Washington Post)
      F. S. Marquardt (Chicago Sun)
      Sergio Osmeña--heavy, some still in Spanish
      Tomas Confesor (in Philippines), June to November, 1943, with correspondence with Quezon re: Panay during war
      J. M. Elizalde
      Sumner Welles
      Harold Ickes (Secretary of Interior)
      Many U.S. Congressmen, especially Representative Bell, Senator Tydings
      Col. Carlos P. Romulo (Information Secretary, Resid. Comm.)
      J. C. Dionigio
      Lt. Col. A. Suriano (Secretary of Finance)
      Eugenio S. Del Rosacio (Re. of Misamis Occidental), esp. 2 page letter (May 14-25, 1943) re: situation in Misamis
      Carlos P. Garcia (Senator, Bohol), esp. 2 page letter to Quezon from "somewhere in Bohol" re: situation in that Province and the Visayas
      Mrs. Pilar Lim (wife Vicente Lim who is in Philippines) re: his loyalty and her sustenance check
      Conrado D. Marapao (Province Governor, Bohol) esp., 2 page letter to Roosevelt (July 17, 1943) re: situation and war in Visayas and Bohol and the funding of anti-Japanese activities
      L. Jesus Cuenco and Miguel Cuenco. Letter (Nov. 6, 1943) to Quezon from Leyte re: some event in Philippines; also 3 page letter Quezon to M. Jesus Cuenco (Jan. 28, 1944)
- Speeches, Articles, Statements, Reports, Interviews, and Book File
  Speech, Article, Statement, Report, Interview, and Book File (1907-1944; Reels 22-46). This series includes handwritten, typewritten, near-print and printed copies of drafts of speeches (some in various stages), articles, remarks, press releases, and press conferences; also manuscript and background materials assembled by Quezon in the writing of his autobiography The Good Fight (if any). The series is arranged by type of material and then chronologically.
  - Speeches, 1909-1913 (Reel 22)
  - Speeches, April 15, 1914-1917 undated (Reel 23)
  - Speeches, 1918-August 2, 1920 (Reel 24)
  - Speeches, August 20, 1920-1921 undated (Reel 25)
  - Speeches, 1921 undated-November 13, 1923 (Reel 26)
  - Speeches, December 7, 1923-September 28, 1925 (Reel 27)
  - Speeches, October 14, 1925-1926 undated (Reel 28)
  - Speeches, 1926 undated-1927 undated (Reel 29)
  - Speeches 1927 undated Articles 1928, 1927-1928 (Reel 30)
  - Miscellaneous writings 1928 Speeches, 1931 (Quezon Report), 1928-1931 (Reel 31)
  - Speeches, October 27, 1931-October 19, 1932 (Reel 32)
  - Speeches, October 26, 1932-July 28, 1933 (Reel 33)
  - Speeches, July 28, 1933; 1933 undated (Reel 34)
  - Speeches 1933 undated Articles, 1933 (Kalaw) (Reel 35)
  - Articles 1933 (Kalaw)-Articles, 1934, 1933-1934 (Reel 36)
  - Speeches, 1935-November 25, 1935 (Reel 37)
  - Speeches, November 25, 1935-Press releases, September 4, 1936 (Reel 38)
  - Press releases September 4, 1936 Speeches, December 25, 1937, 1936-1937 (Reel 39)
  - Speeches December 30, 1937 Miscellaneous writings, 1937 (Reel 40)
  - Speeches January 15, 1938 Articles, 1938 (Reel 41)
  - Speeches, January 6, 1939-August 19, 1939 (Reel 42)
  - Speeches, August 20, 1939-January 22, 1940 (Reel 43)
  - Speeches, May 18, 1940-June 19, 1941 (Reel 44)
  - Speeches, June 19, 1941-May 30, 1943 (Reel 45)
  - Speeches Speech, Article, Statement, Report, Interview File, July 14, 1943 (Reel 46)
- Correspondents File
  Correspondents File (1910-1944; Reels 47-54). This series consists of letters, telegrams, cablegrams, radiograms and memoranda sent and received. It is arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent and then chronologically. The letters in this series are in English unless otherwise indicated.
  - Marcario Adriatico, 1916 (Reel 47)
    (Spanish)
  - Felipe Agoncillo, 1922 (Reel 47)
    (in Spanish and English)
  - Emilio Agoncillo, 1913-1935 (Reel 47)
    (in Spanish, Tagalog, English)
    (much that was not in "General Correspondence",--some clippings re: Aguinaldo's campaign against Quezon (1935))
  - Jose Alejandrino (Senator and later General), 1918-1935 (Reel 47)
    (Spanish with some English)
    (mostly re: his 1924-25 litigation against Quezon)
  - Rafael Alunan, 1910-1937 (Reel 47)
    (includes much of his personal correspondence not found in "General Correspondence")
  - Rosa S. de Arvero (Directora, Instituta de Mujeres), 1920-1930 (Reel 47)
    (in Spanish)
  - Timothy Ansberry (Lawyer, New York), 1916-1929 (Reel 47)
  - Benigno Aquino (Senator), 1920-1935 (Reel 47)
  - Sotero Buluyot, 1918-1937 (Reel 47)
  - H. H. Bandholtz, 1909-1923 (Reel 47)
    (includes some correspondence not found in "General Correspondence")
  - James Blount, 1912-1915 (Reel 47)
    (mostly re: his book and his state of poverty after its completion)
  - Jorge Bocobo, 1923-1931 (Reel 47)
  - Representative William Bor, 1916 (Reel 47)
  - Clement L. Bouve (Lawyer, Washington, D.C.), 1911-1927 (Reel 47)
  - Felipe Buencamino, Jr., 1914-1930 (Reel 47)
  - Frank Carpenter, 1908-1929 (Reel 47)
    (some re: Mindanao, Sulu)
  - Representative H. M. Chalmers, 1927 (Reel 47)